A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests, Series K FA320
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Hospitals
  - Hospitals - Children's Asthma Research Institute and Hospital, 1955-1961 (Box 22, Folder 174)
    Appeals for contributions declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - Children's Asthma Research Institute and Hospital, 1955-1961 (Box 22, Folder 0174A)
  - Hospitals - Children's Hospital Medical Center, 1946-1961 (Box 22, Folder 175)
    1952 Jimmy Fund for children suffering from cancer. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel.
  - Hospitals - Clough Memorial Hospital, Ongole, India, 1912-1928 (Box 22, Folder 176)
    Plans for Hospital as memorial to Dr. Clough. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to Building Fund and toward x-ray equipment. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Rev. James M. Baker.
  - Hospitals - Clough Memorial Hospital, Ongole, India - Aid for Mrs. Clough, 1927-1932 (Box 22, Folder 177)
    Mrs. Clough's pension from Foreign Mission Society; completion of article on Laura Spelman Rockefeller and the Ongole Mission; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to her expenses at Kingston Sanitorium; copy of book on Dr. Clough in the Telagu dialect. Correspondents include E. R. Clough, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Hospitals - Fifth Avenue Hospital, 1920-1922 (Box 22, Folder 178)
    Needs of the Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to endow James Graham Cannon Memorial Room. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Hospitals - French Hospital, 1926-1929, 1939, 1948-1955 (Box 22, Folder 179)
    Needs of the Hospital. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget.
  - Hospitals - Cleveland Homeopathic Hospital, 1901-1910 (Box 23, Folder 180)
  - Hospitals - Huron St. Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio, 1917-1923 (Box 23, Folder 181)
    Need for hospital in East Cleveland; John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s sale of part of Forest Hill estate as hospital site, restrictions on use; gift of additional land for hospital expansion, 1938. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, H. T. Sims, A. L. Boulware, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, J. A. Schlitz.
  - Hospitals - Huron St. Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio, 1924-1945 (Box 23, Folder 182)
  - Hospitals - Lenox Hill Hospital, New York City, 1941-1961 (Box 23, Folder 183)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions, special gift of $42,087 in 1955; suggestion that he have a memorial room or special plaque declined. Other appeals; contributions by Abby Rockefeller Mauzé and John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, William H. Zinsser.
  - Hospitals - Lenox Hill Hospital, New York City - Contributions, 1943-1959 (Box 23, Folder 184)
  - Hospitals - Maine Coast Memorial Hospital, 1948-1961 (Box 23, Folder 185)
    Formerly Eastern Memorial Hospital - a modern hospital for rural community. Hospital not too successful. Name changed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Jones, Clarence C. Little.
  - Hospitals - Mary Hitchcock Memorial Hospital, 1936-1961 (Box 24, Folder 186)
    Mary French Rockefeller's annual contributions. Correspondents include Mary French Rockefeller, David Freeman.
  - Hospitals - Maternity Hospital of Cleveland, 1899-1915 (Box 24, Folder 187)
  - Hospitals - Manhattan Eye, Ear and Throat Hospital, 1946-1960 (Box 24, Folder 188)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s nonrecurring contribution; Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Stanley Resor, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital, 1900-1930 (Box 24, Folder 189)
    Reports of Dr. Beebe's investigations into cancer research; medical needs of Memorial Hospital for the treatment of cancer and allied diseases. John D. Rockefeller's pledge to assist; negotiations between New York Hospital and Cornell Medical Center; letters of thanks from cancer sufferers. Progress in cancer research printed materials; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s membership as Founder Member of the Society of Memorial Cancer Center; his contribution to Children's Village. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Stanley Flexner, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. William B. Coley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital, 1931-1940 (Box 24, Folder 190)
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital, 1941-1961 (Box 24, Folder 191)
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 0191A)
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Pledges for Research, 1927-1940 (Box 24, Folder 192)
    Budgets, hospital needs; payments of pledges of March 17, 1927, June 24, 1927, June 23, 1931. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard, Dr. James Ewing, Dr. William Coley, Thomas B. Appleget.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Ogden White Files, 1950-1953 (Box 25, Folder 193)
    Expansion plans.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - New Building and Site, 1927-1939 (Box 25, Folder 194)
    Letters thanking John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift of site and building for hospital; summary of editorials about gift, resolutions of thanks from hospital. Selection of architects for new hospital. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., S. Flexner, Trevor Arnett.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Contributions, 1948-1961 (Box 25, Folder 195)
    Contributions by members of the family; plaque in memory of Irving Hotchkiss Pardee. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mary Clark Rockefeller, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé Contributions, 1946-1961 (Box 25, Folder 196)
    Regular donations.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - 1949 and 1950 Gifts, 1949-1952 (Box 25, Folder 197)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to endowment fund, construction and teaching program; cancellation of pledge for an unconditional gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - January 8, 1947 Offer of Normandy Realty Company, 1947-1949 (Box 25, Folder 198)
    Transfer of stock of Normandy Realty Corporation to the Memorial Hospital list of officers; appraisal of block between 68th and 69th streets, Second and Third Avenue. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Normandy Realty Company - Letter of Gift, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 199)
    Gift of property for staff housing purposes. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Edward C. Delafield.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Normandy Realty Company - Letter of Approval, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 200)
    Letters of appreciation for gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Normandy Realty Company - James Ewing Memorial Fund, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 201)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to Fund for memorial to Dr. Ewing. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital, 1922-1950 (Box 25, Folder 202)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledges to current maintenance of Hospital, to cost of new elevator and operating room, to x-ray machine, to fun to help rebuild hospital. Letters asking Edsel Ford, A. Atwater Kent and others to contribute; favorable responses. Mrs. Hubbard's gift of elevator in memory of husband; installation of memorial tablet. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s supplemental pledge to indebtedness; contributions by Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary Clark Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller gift, 1961. Annual reports. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Dr. Charles C. Morrison, Edsel Ford, Edward K. Dunham, Mrs. Peter Jay, Mrs. E. Dyer Hubbard, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital, 1922-1950 (Box 25, Folder 0202A)
    Contributions by David Rockefeller and Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital, 1951-1961 (Box 26, Folder 203)
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital, 1951-1961 (Box 26, Folder 0203A)
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Contributions, 1936-1961 (Box 26, Folder 204)
    Contributions by members of the family to current maintenance expenses. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, Edward K. Dunham.
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Campaign for New Wing, 1937-1940 (Box 26, Folder 205)
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Edward K. Dunham Memorial Fund, 1951, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 206)
    Death of Mr. Dunham, establishment of memorial; contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller. Use of fund to purchase elevator. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
    DR material removed to Folder 206A.
  - Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Edward K. Dunham Memorial Fund, 1951, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 0206A)
    Contribution by David Rockefeller. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - National Hospital for Speech Disorders, 1920-1960 (Box 26, Folder 207)
    Mr. Aldrich's praise of Mr. Paine's speech clinic; appeal for contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Richard Aldrich, Albert Bigelow Paine, A. Flexner, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Hospitals - National Jewish Hospital in Denver, 1949-1961 (Box 26, Folder 208)
    Requests for donation to hospital for tuberculosis patients. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Paul Felix Warburg.
  - Hospitals - Neurological Institute, 1909-1947 (Box 26, Folder 209)
    Need for Hospital to care for neurological patients; work of the Hospital; appeal for contributions. Correspondents include S. Flexner, W. H. Welch, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, A. Flexner.
  - Hospitals - New Rochelle Hospital, 1946-1952 (Box 26, Folder 210)
    Nonrecurring gifts by Nelson A. Rockefeller and Winthrop Rockefeller.
    DR material removed to Folder 210A.
  - Hospitals - New Rochelle Hospital, 1946-1952 (Box 26, Folder 0210A)
    Nonrecurring gifts by David Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - New York Foundling Hospital, 1947-1953 (Box 26, Folder 211)
    Work of the Hospital; appeals for contributions; Nelson A. Rockefeller's anonymous contribution toward Christmas party. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - New York Infirmary for Women and Children, 1930-1961 (Box 26, Folder 212)
    Work and needs of the infirmary; requests for contribution. Laurance S. Rockefeller's contributions to building fund; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contribution to library as tribute to Narcissa Cox Vanderlip; Abby Rockefeller Mauz's contribution to Psychiatric Clinic and to Neuropsychiatric Department in memory of Dr. Pardee. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - New York Medical College, 1920-1959 (Box 27, Folder 213)
    Needs of the New York Homeopathic College and Flower Hospital; appeals for contributions. Correspondents include A. Flexner, Thomas B. Appleget, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - New York Skin and Cancer Hospital, 1926-1955 (Box 27, Folder 214)
    S. Flexner's report of hospital's work; appeals for contributions. Correspondents include S. FLexner, Thomas B. Appleget, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Hospitals - New York Throat, Nose, and Lung Hospital, 1904-1920 (Box 27, Folder 215)
    John D. Rockefeller's contribution; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes to Night Camp Auxiliaries. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. G. Beringham.
  - Hospitals - Northern Westchester Hospital Association, 1924, 1947, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 216)
    Need for new hospital to replace Mt. Kisco Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s anonymous contribution. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Northern Westchester Hospital Association, 1924, 1947, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 0216A)
    David Rockefeller's gift. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - Paul Kimball Hospital, Lakewood, New Jersey, 1911-1957 (Box 27, Folder 217)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s contribution to building fund and annual expenses; contribution to maternity ward fund. Correspondents include H. T. Sims, Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Davis.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York, 1952-1956 (Box 27, Folder 218)
    List of Board of Directors, meetings of screening committee, budget, appeals, studies. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Jones.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York, 1957-1961 (Box 27, Folder 219)
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - By-laws, 1953, 1956, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 220)
    Copy of by-laws of Medical Staff and Memorial Hospital Association. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Contributions, 1952-1962 (Box 28, Folder 221)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contributions; his contributions to Carl Miller Memorial. Pledges by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Statements, 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 222)
    Audits. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Minutes, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 223)
    Minutes of meetings of Board of Directors.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - New Building, 1952-1956 (Box 28, Folder 224)
    Selection of architects for the consolidated hospital; proposed plans of operation and organization; progress of building fund campaign; lists of contributors; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's participation in cornerstone-laying ceremony; Opening Day ceremonies. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William J. Yates, S. J. Bolassi.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - New Building - Letters of Appeal, 1952-1955 (Box 28, Folder 225)
    Progress of fund-raising activities; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's letters requesting donations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Expansion Program, 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 226)
    Program; Rockefeller contributions; other contributors. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, D. Freeman.
  - Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Publicity, 1952-1960 (Box 29, Folder 227)
    Newspaper clippings.
  - Hospitals - Presbyterian Hospital, New York, 1924, 1945-1961 (Box 29, Folder 228)
    Reports, activities of the Hospital; appeals for contributions. Abby Rockefeller Mauz gift, Laurance S. Rockefeller gift, others. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, A. Flexner.
  - Hospitals - Psychiatric Institute, Morristown, New Jersey, 1922-1930 (Box 29, Folder 229)
    Inquiry about work of Dr. Allen on diabetes and Bright's disease; further needs of Institute. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, S. Flexner, Frederick M. Allen.
  - Hospitals - Rhode Island Hospital, Providence, Rhode Island, 1925-1926, 1945, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 230)
    Report on Brown University Health Service; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, W. H. P. Faunce.
  - Hospitals - Roosevelt Hospital, New York City, 1940-1961 (Box 29, Folder 231)
    Laying of cornerstone; progress of building campaign; some gifts. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Roosevelt Hospital, New York City - Contributions, 1939-1947, 1949-1961 (Box 29, Folder 232)
    Lists of donors; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s anonymous contribution to enlargement campaign; Abby Rockefeller Milton's contribution; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1960 pledge; 1957 conditional pledge. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Hospitals - Roosevelt Hospital, New York City - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. May 1957 - Pledge and Contribution, 1957-1960 (Box 29, Folder 233)
  - Hospitals - St. Barnabas Hospital for Chronic Disease, 1927, 1943-1956 (Box 29, Folder 234)
    Printed materials; appeals for contributions. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, New York City, 1932, 1943-1961 (Box 29, Folder 235)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s recommendation of Dr. Alan Gregg; appeals for contributions; Abby Rockefeller Milton's contribution; contributions by Mary French Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
  - Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, New York City, 1932, 1943-1961 (Box 29, Folder 0235A)
    Contributions by David Rockefeller. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, New York City - Contributions, 1945-1962 (Box 30, Folder 236)
    From Mary French Rockefeller, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Abby Rockefeller Mauzé.
  - Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, Tokyo, Japan, 1913-1915, 1924-1946, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 237)
    Needs of hospital; laying of cornerstone of Medical Center; progress of construction program; appeals for contributions. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donation to reimburse hospital for earthquake and fire damage. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, George W. Wickersham.
  - Hospitals - St. Ann's Infant Asylum and Maternity Health Home, Cleveland, Ohio, 1911-1912 (Box 30, Folder 238)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - St. Vincent's Hospital, New York City, 1942, 1951-1961 (Box 30, Folder 239)
    Contribution through Davison Fund; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's anonymous contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Alfred E. Smith.
  - Hospitals - General Hospital of Saranac Lake, 1947-1953 (Box 30, Folder 240)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital, 1919, 1929-1961 (Box 30, Folder 241)
    Contributions; Jean Mauzé elected to Board of Governors.
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Contributions, 1940-1962 (Box 30, Folder 242)
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Contributions, 1940-1962 (Box 30, Folder 242A)
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé Contributions, 1940-1949 (Box 30, Folder 243)
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Laurance S. Rockefeller Contributions, 1938-1961 (Box 30, Folder 244)
    Contributions and correspondence. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Westchester Division, 1947-1960 (Box 31, Folder 245)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift for out-patient department; other appeals. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., James H. Wall.
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Westchester Division - Contributions, 1947-1961 (Box 31, Folder 246)
    Gifts from Abby Rockefeller Mauzé.
  - Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Westchester Division - June 1955 Gift, 1954-1956 (Box 31, Folder 247)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Stony Wold Sanatorium, 1901-1948 (Box 31, Folder 248)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions. Recent appeals, declined. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy.
  - Hospitals - Sydenham Hospital, 1943-1949, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 249)
    Fund-raising campaign, budgets and financial reports, activities of the Hospital; anonymous contribution to Fund; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Frank Totten, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital, 1901-1939 (Box 31, Folder 250)
    Later became Phelps Memorial Hospital Association. Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s election to membership in Tarrytown Hospital Association; statistical reports; plans for acquisition of new site and new building. John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to Hospital for maintenance fund, current budgets, special purposes, building fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital, 1940-1952, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 251)
  - Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - April 29, 1950 Gift, 1950-1951 (Box 32, Folder 252)
    Merger of Tarrytown and Ossining hospitals; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge, with provision that pledge be voided if merger plans unsuccessful; voiding of pledge. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - May 1952 Gift, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 253)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge to campaign; drive for new Consolidated Tarrytown-Ossining Hospital; conditions of pledge; change of name to Phelps Memorial Hospital Association. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Dana S. Kreel, Yates, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - Merger with Dobbs Ferry and Ossining Hospitals, 1929, 1935-1948 (Box 32, Folder 254)
    Survey of hospital facilities; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's pledge to underwrite cost; copy of report, "A Survey of the Hospitals of Dobbs Ferry, Ossining and Tarrytown," by Dr. Emerson; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's pledge to survey hospitals to determine advantages of merger. Minutes of meeting of merger subcommittee; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s feeling that name "Rockefeller" should not be used in name of new hospital. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - Merger with Dobbs Ferry and Ossining Hospitals, 1949-1952 (Box 32, Folder 255)
  - Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1935-1952 (Box 32, Folder 256)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd a director; his contributions. Planning and direction.
  - Hospitals - Trudeau Sanatorium, Saranac, New York, 1899-1930 (Box 33, Folder 257)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s donation to current operating expenses; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donations to general fund, laboratory cottage, operating expenses, building fund for research and clinical laboratory. Death of Dr. Trudeau. Contributions by other members of the family. Correspondents include E. L. Trudeau, William H. Welch, Dr. Laurason Broun, Federick Sheffield, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Trudeau Sanatorium, Saranac, New York, 1934-1956 (Box 33, Folder 258)